# **Benedict McElroy**

Preston Pr2 3es mcelroy\_ben@hotmail.com +44 7784 647179

My main skills and experience sit in the financial services sector. I have a highly analytical mind, demonstrated by my first in Philosophy, Politics, and Economics, and I have experience in AML, fraud investigation, and the collections/recoveries aspects of banking.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

#### Personal Details

Driver's License: None

Eligible to work in the UK: Yes

Highest Level of Education: Bachelor's

Total years of experience: 3

# Work Experience

#### **Branch Assistant**

Ramsdens Financial Ltd - Preston February 2022 to October 2022

In this role I conduct foreign currency transactions, buy gold from customers, implement pawnbroking loans and act as an agent for Western Union transactions. I have had to liaise with the Compliance department and carry out Anti-Money Laundering training modules, as this is something the business takes very seriously. If the frequency, regularity, magnitude, or destination of the transactions alters significantly, it is my duty to enact an Enhanced Compliance Form, which I have had to do on multiple occasions. This form requires extra details from the customer regarding the nature of the transaction and the reasons for conducting it. We must also take scans of customer ID documents and keep them securely on file, in order to make sure that transactions are logged correctly against the correct customer and to ensure that fraudulent activity is not being facilitated. With Western Union transactions, if there is any reason to suspect that fraudulent activity or external pressure is being placed on the customer to conduct the transaction, we are obliged to raise an alert (a Suspicious Activity Report – SAR) with Western Union regarding this, so that they can review the transaction against the account and decide whether the transaction is valid, or if a block should be placed on the account.

#### **Financial Assistance Agent**

Randstad Sourceright
July 2020 to December 2020

Randstad Sourceright are a temping agency. This was a continuation of the role described below, working for Barclays in the BFA Unsecured Collections department, working from home. My temporary contract came to an end on December 16, 2020, and I was offered a transition to a permanent role, which I decided not to take at the time, as I was seeking a part-time role to manage external commitments.

### **Financial Assistance Agent**

Resource Solutions July 2019 to July 2020

Resource Solutions are an agency. I applied to Barclays. I began work at Barclays Bank PLC in July 2019 in the BFA Unsecured Collections department, as a Financial Assistance Agent on a temporary basis.

This role is multi-skilled, so I can take both Barclays Financial Assistance and Collections calls. Each call involves evaluating if a customer is in financial difficulty by having an open conversation regarding why they are calling and what support we may be able to offer based on their financial situation.

I have to exercise my excellent computer and telephony skills such as active listening and screen navigation on every call, as well as problem-solving to choose the correct support for the customer's situation, and attention to detail to make sure the support is put in place and set up correctly.

#### **Employment Gap**

February 2019 to July 2019

Between February 2019 and July 2019 I was seeking employment, having moved from Preston to Manchester. I wanted to find a role that was right for me, which led me to apply for Barclays.

#### **Customer Services Agent**

Hinduja Global Solutions UK - Preston August 2017 to February 2019

is an outsourcer. The campaign I was assigned to was a company called Fleur Telecom, a telecoms company who specialise in rural areas. They acquired most of their initial business base from TalkTalk. My role was a Customer Services Agent. I took inbound calls from customers on a range of queries, encompassing tech support, customer service, and complaints, amongst others. I also dealt with assigning service credits to customers. This involved extensive use of Excel in order to assess the entitlement of customers to varying levels of credit, depending on whether they fit the qualifying criteria. I was often called upon to assist new starters on the campaign and I would be seated with them to offer one-to-one support during their induction process.

#### **Google Online Marketing Challenge**

2017 to 2017

I was selected as one of four candidates to represent the University of York in this global marketing competition. We had to run an online marketing campaign using Google Adwords, for a business based in York called Ainsty Ales. As a team we had to divide our labour efficiently by allocating tasks based on team members' strengths and weaknesses. I took the opportunity to learn the operational side of Google Adwords and am now confident I could run an online marketing campaign with no assistance.

#### Film and Television Editor

The Yorker 2015 to 2017

An independent and online magazine based in York. I was responsible for overseeing and editing a team of writers for this section, as well as liaising with cinemas and film festival representatives to secure coverage for their events in and around the York area, notably for the Aesthetica Short Film Festival (ASFF).

# Co-founder and Secretary of the University of York Marketing and Advertising Society

2014 to 2015

I decided to set this society up with some classmates as I thought it odd that there was no society which fit this description when I joined university. I was involved in getting guest speakers from industry in to speak, and setting up and advertising our events throughout campus. My personal favourite was securing the Managing Director of a virtual reality company called Chronicles VR to come and give a talk on setting up and marketing a start-up business.

## Education

# **BA Hons Degree in Philosophy, Politics and Economics**

University of York

June 2017

#### Skills

- Finance
- Customer service
- Jewellery sales (Less than 1 year)
- Pawnbroking (Less than 1 year)
- Pawnbroking (Less than 1 year)
- Foreign Currency (Less than 1 year)
- Financial services (3 years)